<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bitcoin-Blockchain-Cryptocurrencies</title>
    <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bitcoin-Blockchain-Cryptocurrencies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:33:54 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:33:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/introduction/</guid>
      <description>It all started with the Bitcoin Whitepaper by Satoshi Nakamoto, released in 2008. Although this whitepaper presents the core idea behind Bitcoin, it is extremely important to study the Bitcoin Source Code to appreciate the true beauty of the Bitcoin protocol. The Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies book by Narayanan et al. and the Mastering Bitcoin book by Antonopoulos are great resources to understand the intricate technical details of Bitcoin. The Coursera course on Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies goes hand-in-hand with the book by Narayanan et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography</title>
      <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:35:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/cryptography/</guid>
      <description>While Bitcoin and traditional blockchain frameworks only borrow standard mechanisms of data digest (hash functions) and entity authentication (digital signatures) from cryptography, the next generation of Cryptocurrencies and Blockchain frameworks have adopted more sophisticated cryptographic tools to address the key issues of traceability and scalability. Considering this, it is important to study a few core modules of cryptography, as follows.
 Introduction to Cryptography &amp;mdash; Chapter 1 of the Boneh-Shoup Book</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consensus</title>
      <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/consensus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:36:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/consensus/</guid>
      <description>Consensus is the essence of Bitcoin, Blockchain and Cryptocurrency technologies. While the Bitcoin Whitepaper presented the classic Nakamoto consensus in 2008, it took a number of years to formally present the analysis of the Bitcoin Backbone Protocol. This seminal work by Garay et al. (2014) has been followed up by a number of theoretical analysis of blockchain protocols in the last few years. The following technical papers are must-reads in this context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralization</title>
      <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/decentralization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:36:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/decentralization/</guid>
      <description>The Bitcoin Whitepaper envisaged a distributed network of peers incentivised to honestly maintain a global ledger. However, the same incentives resulted in a concentration of power in the Bitcoin mining network, and eventually, the maintenance of the ledger converged to a handful of miners and mining pools. Game Theoretic analysis of Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency incentive design is a fascinating topic. The following works are must-reads in this direction.
 Analysis of Bitcoin Pooled Mining Reward Systems &amp;mdash; Rosenfeld (2011)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalability</title>
      <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/scalability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:36:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/scalability/</guid>
      <description>With the adoption of Cryptocurrencies and Blockchain Technology at a dizzying pace, it is of prime importance to reconsider the issues of network scalability and transaction latency. While Bitcoin supports a maximum of 7 tx/sec with a confirmation time of 10 minutes, Visa or Mastercard registers thousands of transactions per second, with lightning confirmation. Thus the most utilitarian research problem is whether decentralized blockchains can be scaled up to match the desired performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/anonymity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:36:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/anonymity/</guid>
      <description>Anonymity is a cornerstone of decentralization, and Cryptocurrencies have historically treated anonymity with utmost importance. While Bitcoin only provides pseudonymity and needs mixing networks for privacy, Monero goes one step ahead with ring signatures, and ZeroCash takes it forward with zero-knowledge proofs. Still, to date, de-anonymization and traceability are hot topics for research. The following works are must-reads in this direction.
 A Fistful of Bitcoins &amp;mdash; Meiklejohn et al. (2013)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security</title>
      <link>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:36:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sgsourav.github.io/bbctech/security/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>